ontariocolleges.ca 2017-11-23

# Privacy Statement | ontariocolleges.ca

OCAS Application Services Inc., (Ontario College Application Service or OCAS) is committed to protecting the privacy of your personal, including website activity (see [Terms of Use](http://www.ontariocolleges.ca/terms-of-use)), academic information and other school records ("Personal Information"). The Personal Information referenced in this application, and related materials, is collected, used or disclosed in accordance with the relevant statutory and regulatory provisions of the _Ministry of Agriculture, Food and Rural Affairs Act_ , R.S.O. 1990, c. M.16 and the _Ministry of Training, Colleges and Universities Act_ , R.S.O. 1990, c. M.19, and the _Education Act_ , R.S.O. 1990, c E.2.

Your Personal Information will be collected, used and disclosed primarily for the purpose of making admissions and accreditation related decisions, including the creation, processing and maintenance of your application, acceptance and registration with the Colleges, as well as to assign, verify, retrieve and/or validate your Ontario Education Number (OEN), as well as updating Personal Information associated with the OEN.

In order to facilitate the application process and improve data accuracy, you consent to and authorize OCAS to collect use, and disclose your Personal Information, whether obtained directly from you or other relevant sources, including but not limited to previous institutions which you have attended, the Ontario Universities Application Centre ("OUAC") and any relevant government ministries. Authorized use may also include OCAS updating third party databases, such as those maintained by relevant government ministries and other institutions, to ensure information accuracy and consistency.

OCAS must disclose your Personal Information in order to process your application or other services, acceptance or registration. Personal Information may also be used by OCAS and/or disclosed to the Colleges, the Ministry of Advanced Education and Skills Development, and entities with which they do business, as well as the Ministry of Education, the Ministry of Agriculture, Food and Rural Affairs and the Ministry of Health, as well as other educational research agencies approved by OCAS, for statistical, marketing and research purposes. Consistent with these purposes, your Personal Information may also be linked with student information databases maintained by the college which you eventually choose to attend in order to develop and maintain appropriate policies, programs and funding mechanisms.

OCAS may also make your Personal Information available, as minimally required, to third parties who provide services, such as international accreditation or integrity audits to protect our systems and your Personal Information. In addition, OCAS will disclose the minimally required Personal Information to facilitate specialized third-party services such as live chat or credit card processing.

Your Personal Information may be collected, used and / or disclosed in jurisdictions outside of Ontario.

You therefore consent to and authorize OCAS to disclose your Personal Information to individuals, organizations and institutions that require such information for program monitoring, research, funding purposes, accreditation, student financial aid applications, or are involved with the processing of your application, acceptance or registration. These entities include, but are not limited to the Colleges, associated universities (e.g. for those applying to collaborative or joint programs), Ontario high school counselors and / or other support staff (for those currently enrolled in high school), third party service providers, and relevant provincial and federal ministries or agencies.

It is your responsibility to make sure that the information is truthful, complete and correct, failing which your application may be delayed or invalidated. You must also take appropriate measures to safeguard login information and any printed copies of the completed application.

Your Personal Information will be retained at OCAS offices and/or secure offsite facilities.

You should note that copies of your Personal Information may be retained by those entities to which OCAS provides disclosure to facilitate your application and / or services. Any concerns you may have with respect to access, retention and/or protection of your Personal Information held by elsewhere should be directed to the applicable entity, e.g. the Colleges who are subject to the _Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act_.

For more information about the collection, use, disclosure and protection of your Personal Information at OCAS, review OCAS' [Privacy Code](http://www.ontariocolleges.ca/privacy/privacy-code) or call OCAS' Privacy Officer at: 519.763.2363 ext. 6816 or email the Privacy Officer at: [privacyofficer@ocas.ca](mailto:privacyofficer@ocas.ca).

**Privacy Code**

The Privacy Code informs you of the principles and guidelines which OCAS uses to protect the personal information of individuals that we collect, use or disclose in the course of our operations. Review the OCAS [Privacy Code](http://www.ontariocolleges.ca/privacy/privacy-code).
